IBRAHIM ABDULGANIYU

Lagos State, Nigeria



abdulganiyutechng@gmail.com



07039901318



linkedin.com/in/ibrahimxtech



https://abdulganiyu.vercel.app

Summary

Experience: 2+ years of total experience, with a focus on Frontend web/mobile engineering.

Skills: Proficient in Javascript, Typescript, React, React Native, Redux, Redux toolkit Query, and GraphQL. Experienced in all stages of advanced web/mobile development, from design and installation to testing and maintenance. Skilled in user interface and API development, testing, and debugging.

Career Highlights:

Led the successful development and launch of a customer-facing mobile app, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement and a 20% boost in customer satisfaction.

Conceptualized and implemented a streamlined UI/UX design process, reducing development time by 15% and leading to more user-friendly interfaces across web and mobile platforms.

Collaborated as a key team member on LASMAB CMS and Board management app that achieved a 50% improvement in web and mobile system performance, enhancing overall user experience and reducing load times.

Experience

• techleaders Full Stack Engineer

Tech Leaders

Jun 2023 - Present (5 months)

- Enhanced automated testing methods, leading to a 20% reduction in testing time and more efficient development processes.
- Achieved 100% efficiency and significantly improved application speed by rigorously testing and implementing program modifications.
- Conceptualized, built, analyzed, and led the deployment of multiple software applications, resulting in increased operational efficiency and user satisfaction.

Lead Facilitator and Frontend Engineer

NUPAT TECHNOLOGIES

Sep 2021 - Present (2 years 2 months)

- Developed and maintained web applications utilizing a tech stack encompassing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, React Native, Node.js, and MySQL.
- · Collaborated extensively with cross-functional teams to conceptualize, develop, and successfully implement new features and functionalities, enhancing overall product offerings.
- Optimized web application performance for superior speed and scalability, resulting in an improved user experience.

• Teach and imapact frontend (React and React Native) and backend skills (Nodejs and expressjs) on cohorts.



Frontend Developer

affilBase

Apr 2022 - Jul 2023 (1 year 4 months)

- Successfully transitioned existing React web applications to React Native, improving user experiences and expanding our mobile presence.
- Meticulously crafted pixel-perfect and seamless user interfaces across diverse mobile platforms, ensuring a consistent and visually appealing user experience.
- Built and published a mobile app, making it available on both the App Store and Google Play Store, broadening our digital reach and impact.

Education



関 University of Ilorin

Bachelor's Degree, Social Work 2015 - 2019

Licenses & Certifications



Frontend Diploma - NUPAT TECHNOLOGIES

Skills

css • javascript • mysql • React.js • React Native • Node.js • TypeScript • Git • HTML5 • Web Development